hireright.com 2017-06-22

# HireRight Privacy Policy | HireRight

English | Español

As a consumer reporting agency governed by the federal Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA) among other applicable state and federal laws, HireRight is committed to protecting your privacy.

This Privacy Policy covers HireRight's web site, and HireRight's practices for handling personal information provided to HireRight over the Internet by the general public using HireRight's publicly available web site. This Policy also covers personal information provided by HireRight's clients, and their job applicants and employees (as well as other individuals who have given their written authorization for HireRight's clients to conduct a background investigation on them), using HireRight's online background screening solution that is accessible only through an access-restricted portion of HireRight's web site. HireRight will collect, store, and use personally identifiable information only in compliance with applicable law, including the FCRA.

**Information Collection**

When you browse HireRight's publicly accessible web site, you do so anonymously. HireRight collects personally identifiable information from you only if you choose to provide this information to us. In some instances, HireRight may collect non-personal (e.g., aggregate or demographic) data through cookies. This information is used to better understand and improve the usability, performance and effectiveness of the HireRight.com web site, as is further described below under "Cookies and Tracking Technology".   
The types of personal information we may collect about you through our publicly accessible web site include the following (should you decide to provide such information to HireRight): (a) contact and identifying information (e.g., name, address, e-mail address, phone and fax numbers, employer(s), job title) in connection with your expression of interest in receiving information about, or your registering for, HireRight products or services, newsletters and conferences; (b) your resume information and employment application information in response to HireRight job openings; and (c) any other personal information that you may voluntarily provide to us in an online form or through an e-mail.

Access to certain HireRight web pages and online services is not available to the general public and requires a login code and password provided by HireRight. Those web pages, and the information downloadable to and from those pages, are made available only to clients of HireRight. On these web pages, HireRight collects only information that the user voluntarily shares with HireRight.

If you are using this web site to open an employment screening account with HireRight, we collect the information requested on our account application form, including contact information and financial information (such as credit card number or billing information). This information is used for internal purposes, such as account establishment, billing, fulfillment of orders and customer service.

**How We Use Your Personal Information**

When your personal information is collected on HireRight's publicly accessible web site, HireRight will inform you at the point of collection of the purpose for the collection. HireRight will use your personal information only in the way we specify when it is collected unless you consent to a different use.

For example, HireRight may use personal information submitted in an account application to set up and maintain your account. HireRight also may use the personal information you provide to answer your questions and inquiries, to support HireRight's own recruitment activities in response to your inquiries into HireRight's job postings, and to provide newsletters and other information (if any) that you have requested.

If you have provided your personal information over this web site in connection with a background screen ordered by HireRight's client - HireRight may use your personal information to perform your background screen for that client. HireRight will not use your information to conduct a background screening investigation and create a report unless HireRight's client has provided a certification required by the FCRA and any other applicable law. In this certification, HireRight's client certifies to HireRight that it has a legally permissible purpose for ordering the background screen, and that it has, to the extent required by applicable law, obtained your informed consent to conduct the background screen.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

HireRight does not sell or rent personal information to third parties. HireRight will not disclose your personal information to a third party without your permission, except in connection with performing your background screen for HireRight's client or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.

HireRight may disclose personal information as necessary or appropriate in connection with any of the purposes for which we use personal information as described above in "How We Use Your Personal Information".

When HireRight conducts a background screening investigation about you, HireRight may disclose information that you submit through this web site to the HireRight client that ordered a background screening investigation on you. HireRight also may disclose your information to certain third parties as necessary to conduct the background investigation (such as educational institutions, prior employers, courts, law enforcement agencies and other persons or entities that may provide or verify information about you), as well as to a third-party representative or subcontractor authorized by HireRight to assist in the background screening investigation. These third party representatives and subcontractors include service providers that help host or support the web site or otherwise provide technical assistance, court researchers and other data and service vendors. HireRight transfers to these representatives and subcontractors only the personal information they need to deliver to HireRight (for the benefit of HireRight's client) the requested product or service. HireRight prohibits these third parties from using that information for any other purpose. HireRight requires that these parties maintain commercially reasonable measures to protect the confidentiality of your information.

HireRight also may in good faith disclose personal information and any other additional information available to HireRight for any of the following purposes: (i) investigate, prevent or take action regarding actual or suspected illegal activities or fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or violations of HireRight's terms of use; (ii) respond to or defend against subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; (iii) establish or exercise HireRight's legal rights; or (iv) otherwise comply with applicable law.

HireRight may acquire other businesses, and other businesses may acquire HireRight. If that occurs, the information HireRight collects may be one of the assets examined or transferred as part of the transaction. HireRight will not permit another business to examine the information HireRight has collected without a confidentiality agreement and only to the extent permitted by law. HireRight will not transfer the information it has collected unless the recipient agrees to provide privacy protections equal to or exceeding those established by this Privacy Policy.

**Personal Information Disclosure: United States or Overseas**

Personal information submitted to HireRight for a background screening investigation may at times be transferred outside of the United States in order to perform the background investigation. All personal information will be transmitted and stored in a secure manner in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

**Cookies and Tracking Technology**

HireRight's web site may use the standard technology called a "cookie" to collect information about how you use the web site.

A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to your hard drive and used for record-keeping purposes. A cookie file can contain information such as the URL you came from, your computer's IP address (i.e., the Internet address of your computer) and domain type (e.g., .com or .org, etc.), your browser type, the country, state and telephone area code where your server is located, the pages of our site that were viewed during a visit, and any search terms that you entered on our site. This information is used for internal purposes only, and we do not link your URL or IP address to any personal information unless you have logged into our web site with a HireRight account login and password.  In addition, HireRight’s web site does not allow other parties to collect personally identifiable information about an individual consumer’s online activities over time and across different Web sites when a consumer uses the HireRight web site.

If you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies, although it is possible that some areas of our web site will not function properly if you do so. In particular, you may be required to accept cookies in order to complete certain actions on HireRight's web site.  HireRight’s web site does not currently recognize “do not track” signals transmitted by web browsers. 

**Security**

HireRight is committed to protecting the personal information that HireRight receives about consumers. While we cannot guarantee the security of that information, we utilize a combination of online and offline security technologies, procedures and organizational measures to help safeguard consumer information against loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

We employ Secure Socket Layer (SSL) data encryption when data is transmitted over the Internet to our web site. We have installed layered firewalls and other security technologies to help prevent unauthorized access to our systems. Strong password protection protocols are used on our computers, and employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy policies. The servers used to store consumer information are maintained in a secure environment with appropriate security measures.

**Links**

HireRight's web site may provide links to third-party web sites. Please be aware that those third-party web sites are outside of our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. If you have questions about how another site uses your information, consult that site's privacy statement.

**Your Ability to Review or Modify Personal Information, or Unsubscribe.**

HireRight strives to protect the quality and integrity of your personal information. If you have provided your personal information (such as zip code, phone, e-mail or postal address) to HireRight while browsing HireRight's publicly accessible web site, and wish to update such personal information (if any) that you have provided us, please e-mail us at [custome](mailto:customerservice@hireright.com)[rservice@hireright.com](mailto:customerservice@hireright.com). Also, if you wish to unsubscribe from any of our newsletters or other communications for which you have registered, you may e-mail us at [feedback@hireright.com](mailto:feedback@hireright.com). If you are a HireRight client with a registered account, you may review (and update) your account information by logging into your account. If you are an individual on whom a HireRight client has requested a background screening investigation, and have submitted personal information to HireRight at the request of such client for purposes of procuring a background report, then you can review your HireRight file in accordance with your file disclosure rights under the Fair Credit Reporting Act, California Civil Code Section 1786.22 and any other applicable state laws by contacting HireRight's Customer Service Department at [customerservice@hireright.com](mailto:customerservice@hireright.com). [Click to review a summary of your consumer rights (including file disclosure rights) under the Fair Credit Reporting Act.](http://www.hireright.com/PDFs/FTCConsumerRights.pdf)

**Children Under Age 13**

HireRight does not offer services to children under the age of 13, and this web site is not directed to children under the age of 13. HireRight does not knowingly collect information about children under the age of 13.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

HireRight may revise this policy from time to time. If there is a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will post the revised policy at this location. HireRight will not provide less privacy protection, without your consent, to information collected under a prior privacy policy. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to be informed of how HireRight is protecting your information.

**Contact Us**

_Questions about a current background check:_

If your background check is currently being performed by HireRight and you have questions or need assistance, please contact our Customer Service department: 

HireRight Customer Service Phone: 866-521-6995

HireRight Customer Service Email: [customerservice@hireright.com](mailto:customerservice@hireright.com).

_Report Requests and Disputes:_

If you would like to request a copy of your background report(s) (if any) prepared by HireRight and/or your active database files (if any) maintained on you by HireRight; or to dispute the accuracy of the information in your background report, please go to http://www.hireright.com/applicants for links that will provide you with details on all of the options (online, phone, fax and mail) that are available to you.

_Privacy Policy questions:_

If you have any questions specifically regarding our _privacy policy_ , you may contact us at:

Julie Duffner  
3349 Michelson Dr., Suite 150.  
Irvine, CA 92612  
(949) 794-5451  

In accordance with California Civil Code § 1786.20, the representative named above will be able to assist you with additional information regarding our privacy practices and policies in the event of a compromise of your information.

Effective Date: January 1, 2014  
(Contact information updated August 2016)
